<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Budget on Battle of Brothers</title>
    <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/tags/budget/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Budget on Battle of Brothers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 20:02:58 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://battleofbrothers.com/tags/budget/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>$1500 on Music</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/1500-on-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 20:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/1500-on-music/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve entered into a contract with Brendon Williams to compose the game&amp;#8217;s music. He&amp;#8217;ll be doing everything from intro music, battle music, world map music, and any other types of music that come up. Brendon recently started with the music for the intro movie and it&amp;#8217;s sounding awesome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$7323 on Animations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/7323-on-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/7323-on-animations/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve received a bunch of animations over the last few months and you can see a lot of them over at Dualbo&amp;#8217;s Vimeo Site and in my status updates. I&amp;#8217;ve received 12 of the 18 characters that will be in the game, so we&amp;#8217;re two-thirds there. I think this payment has officially put my game over budget, but that&amp;#8217;s how these things go sometimes. The good news is that the animations are awesome and worth every penny.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$2500 on Illustrations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/2500-on-illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 19:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/2500-on-illustrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This expense wasn&amp;#8217;t a lump sum payment, but 4 payments made over the course of a couple months. I&amp;#8217;m extended the original contract with the illustrator because the game has more artwork than I originally anticipated. The following illustrations were done for this update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$300 for Script Editor</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/02/13/300-for-script-editor/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Feb 2015 19:56:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/02/13/300-for-script-editor/</guid>
      <description>Back in our Particletree days, we had a friend copy edit any major pieces we wrote. Inevitably, she would catch something that was poorly written. So, for a game that contains almost 15 minutes of dialogue, I figured that I would have to spend money on a second pair of eyes to help me out. Early on in the process, Mike Waterston emailed me with a desire to help out. He wasn&amp;#8217;t in it for the money &amp;#8212; he just wanted to help a game come to life.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$375 for a Music Tryout</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/22/375-for-a-music-tryout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Jan 2015 14:38:35 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/22/375-for-a-music-tryout/</guid>
      <description>Every once in awhile, a composer will email me asking if I would like for them to work on the project. I keep their names with the idea of getting back to them when I&amp;#8217;m ready to focus on music. Anthony contacted me out of the blue with an eagerness, varied skill set, and past experience &amp;#8212; all which compelled me to start a trial. So far, trial is going great.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$7600 on Illustrations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/13/7600-on-illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Jan 2015 14:24:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/13/7600-on-illustrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This expense wasn&amp;#8217;t a lump sum payment, but about 10 payments made over the course of a few months. I&amp;#8217;m at the end of my original contract with an illustrator, and so far he&amp;#8217;s delivered:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$1829 on Animations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/11/17/1829-on-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Nov 2014 14:10:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/11/17/1829-on-animations/</guid>
      <description>Two more characters were completed, which brings me to a total of 4 characters. This expense was about $450 more than I had originally budgeted for due to the unexpected time associated with animating weapons. Basically, characters with weapons will cost a little bit more to animate, and I&amp;#8217;m fine with that.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$588 on Corona SDK Pro Subscription</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/10/20/588-on-corona-sdk-pro-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 13:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/10/20/588-on-corona-sdk-pro-subscription/</guid>
      <description>I was using Corona&amp;#8217;s free product for awhile, but I decided to upgrade to the pro subscription once I continuously encounter bugs with live builds on the free trial. My game is still a ways off from completion, and I wish I could have used the free trial problem free for a little bit longer, but I knew I&amp;#8217;d have to fork up the money eventually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animations for $8,095</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/22/animations-for-8095/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Sep 2014 13:35:21 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/22/animations-for-8095/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Just as I have been working nearly non stop with an illustrator, I have been going back and forth with Liron, my animator. I eased into a contract with her due to fear from my last animation contract. We started with a $90 trial, and then another $500 trial. She did an amazing job on those, so the full contract began.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$3733 on Illustrations and Animations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/09/3733-on-illustrations-and-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 19:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/09/3733-on-illustrations-and-animations/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been working with the an illustrator and animator for a few weeks now they&amp;#8217;ve produced the world map, multiple battlefield maps, concept characters, character turnarounds, and 2 animated characters (semi produced). I&amp;#8217;m pretty close to staying on budget so far, but I can see how both artists could end up costing a bit more than I originally thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$8,380 on Illustration Contract</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/01/8380-on-illustration-contract/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2014 13:29:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/01/8380-on-illustration-contract/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Chris, Scott and I came to an agreement on an illustration contract that would involve Scott alternating weeks in which he works for us. My portion of the contract was $8,000. It ended up finishing mid-week, so I extended it the extra $380 to round it off. The goal was to finish all illustrations for the game during this time. That did not happen because I changed my game midway through. Still, a lot was accomplished.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$96 on Trial Animations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/96-on-trial-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 14:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/96-on-trial-animations/</guid>
      <description>I had a couple of animators create test animations off of one of my character concepts just to see if their style fit what I have in mind for the game. Both animators were able to mock up a 3D animation in about 3 hours. Neither of the trial animators was the right fit for me this time around, but I&amp;#8217;ll hold onto their contact information for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$800 on Illustrations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/800-on-illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 14:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/800-on-illustrations/</guid>
      <description>I found an illustrator for my game, and he started out by creating some character concepts and a couple of battlefield scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$200 on Behance</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/200-on-behance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/200-on-behance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been looking for an animator and the three methods of recruitment that I used were making a blog post, reaching out to people I admired on Carbonmade, and paying for a job listing on Behance. I received 52 applications within 5 days and ended up finding the right man for the job through Behance. If he works out, then this was $200 well spent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Half of Animation Contract: $1,558</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/26/first-half-of-animation-contract-1558/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 13:20:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/26/first-half-of-animation-contract-1558/</guid>
      <description>I wrote about a contract that I broke before it was finished, and this amount accounts for that mistake. Our contracts are structured in a way that either party can leave, and payments are spread out. Anything paid is no refundable, and anything completed must be delivered. This allows flexibility for both parties.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$325 on Illustrator Trial Run</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/18/325-on-illustrator-trial-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 15:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/18/325-on-illustrator-trial-run/</guid>
      <description>I made a list of illustrators who I planned on contacting for trial illustrations, but I lucked out by having Scott Pellico go first. Scott illustrated a piece of my world map as a trial to see if his style was a fit for the world I&amp;#8217;d like to create. He nailed it and I&amp;#8217;m lucky to have found a quality illustrator on the first go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$249 and trials are completed</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/17/249-and-trials-are-completed/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Aug 2014 13:16:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/17/249-and-trials-are-completed/</guid>
      <description>More, more, more trials. Finally, I&amp;#8217;ve found an animator and an illustrator. Ready to begin contracts with both. This brings my trial budget up to $1,483.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$475 on Animator Trial Runs</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/08/375-on-animator-trial-runs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Aug 2014 16:47:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/08/375-on-animator-trial-runs/</guid>
      <description>Things are moving quickly now. I&amp;#8217;ve started to line up as many character artists and animators as I can to do some trial runs. Ideally, I&amp;#8217;ll find one super talented person, or multiple people who have complimentary skill sets. Trials get expensive, but they&amp;#8217;re worth it to find the right person. More should come in next week.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keep the concept art coming with $424</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/30/keep-the-concept-art-coming-with-424/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Jul 2014 15:48:07 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/30/keep-the-concept-art-coming-with-424/</guid>
      <description>It turns out finding a final style is harder than I thought. Ran more experiments with both an animator and illustrator this week to try to merge their styles / find a final appearance for the game.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Trial run with an animator for $135</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/26/trial-run-with-an-animator-for-135/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Jul 2014 16:02:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/26/trial-run-with-an-animator-for-135/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve found an animator who I like working with, so I decide to start a trial with him. The main objective is to figure out an art style that works with my illustrator, and to get a rough idea on pricing in that given style. I&amp;#8217;ll share the result when they come in.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$200 on Trial Art</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/23/200-on-trial-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 17:23:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/23/200-on-trial-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m starting to reach out to a few artists, and it is difficult to determine cost, style, availability and friendliness just by exchanging a few emails. So, I plan to contract out a couple of artists to see their take on my existing level and characters. In the end, I imagine I&amp;#8217;ll spend $1,000 on this sort of purchase.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spent $105.93 for Apple Developer</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/23/spent-105-93-for-apple-developer/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 23 Jul 2014 17:19:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/23/spent-105-93-for-apple-developer/</guid>
      <description>To be an Apple Developer, you have to register with their developer program. I have no problem paying the $99+tax since I love the developer program they have in place. I enjoy working in Xcode, notice fast download speeds, frequent beta updates, and so on. Overall, it is a pleasant environment to work in, so please take my money.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Texture Packer and Physics Editor for $50</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/18/texture-packer-and-physics-editor-for-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 19:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/18/texture-packer-and-physics-editor-for-50/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I could avoid throwing down any cash for sprite sheet development, but I finally broke down and purchased &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codeandweb.com&#34;&gt;Texture Packer&lt;/a&gt;. They just make sprite sheet creation too easy, and the tool spits out exactly what the Corona SDK needs to render and scale sprites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Spent $15 on video tutorials</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/27/spent-15-on-video-tutorials/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 15:02:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/27/spent-15-on-video-tutorials/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m not usually a fan of books, or any tutorial for that matter. I prefer to look at docs and start playing around. But since I know so little about game development, it makes sense to look at someone else&amp;#8217;s code and project to get an idea of their code structure and approach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Game design books for $80.80</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/3-game-design-books-for-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/3-game-design-books-for-80/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;#8217;d kick this contest off by purchasing a little bed time reading material. I want to start prototyping games as soon as possible, so hopefully a few books on game theory and design will help me to avoid some of the mistakes beginners make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>