<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Learning on Battle of Brothers</title>
    <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/tags/learning/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Learning on Battle of Brothers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 17:37:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://battleofbrothers.com/tags/learning/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year Later – Late and Over Budget</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/08/one-year-later-late-and-over-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 17:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/08/one-year-later-late-and-over-budget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks the one year anniversary of our &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com&#34;&gt;game development competition&lt;/a&gt;, so I can now safely say that the game will be late. Not only will the game be late, but I&amp;#8217;m also about &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/budget&#34;&gt;2k over budget&lt;/a&gt;. If you had asked me a year ago if I would be disappointed about being late and over budget, I would have absolutely said yes.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating a Path Using Image Masking</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/animating-a-path-using-image-masking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 18:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/animating-a-path-using-image-masking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently found myself wanting to animate a character&amp;#8217;s progress path and initially I thought I would do this by creating multiple animation frames, much like a sprite. After a bit of frustration, trial and error, I realized that creating an image mask was a more efficient and effective method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you an example of what I was trying to accomplish, here is a picture of a portion of my game&amp;#8217;s world map. The yellow and line is the path that my character takes.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning an Image but Not a Mask in Corona SDK</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/transitioning-an-image-but-not-a-mask-in-corona-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/transitioning-an-image-but-not-a-mask-in-corona-sdk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently playing around with image masking, and I wanted to transition the mask so that the image behind it gradually appeared on screen. Unfortunately, Corona doesn&amp;#8217;t allow you to transition masks, but after &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/34774-moving-image-but-not-mask/&#34;&gt;doing a little research&lt;/a&gt; I learned that you can use groups to transition the image behind the mask. Here&amp;#8217;s an example to see what I&amp;#8217;m talking about.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How To Implement Squads and Formations, Part 1</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/08/how-to-implement-squads-and-formations-part-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Sep 2014 18:38:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/08/how-to-implement-squads-and-formations-part-1/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There is an awesome article on Gamasutra about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/131720/coordinated_unit_movement.php?page=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Coordinated Unit Movement&lt;/a&gt;. They also have a companion post about &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.gamasutra.com/view/feature/131721/implementing_coordinated_movement.php?page=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;implementing said movement&lt;/a&gt;. However, the posts are from 1999, and they deal mainly in pseudocode. Also, I&amp;#8217;m convinced there is absolutely nothing else on the entire internet explaining the topic. So, an experienced developer may be able to read the ideas and know how to implement them, but it has been a bit of a struggle for me as a new developer. I&amp;#8217;m going to try to document a step by step implementation of formations, squads, and movement for someone who hasn&amp;#8217;t done it before. I&amp;#8217;ll be writing in Swift / Sprite Kit, but the code should be easy enough for anyone to follow. I also welcome corrections / improvements from experts.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Backgrounds for Multiple Aspect Ratios and Corona’s Config.lua</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/26/designing-backgrounds-for-multiple-aspect-ratios-and-coronas-config-lua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 13:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/26/designing-backgrounds-for-multiple-aspect-ratios-and-coronas-config-lua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I chose Corona SDK as my development platform was because they support many devices across many platforms. But mo&amp;#8217; devices means mo&amp;#8217; problems, and one of those problems is creating artwork that scales across all devices.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Memory Usage in Sprite Kit</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/25/memory-usage-in-sprite-kit/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Aug 2014 14:58:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/25/memory-usage-in-sprite-kit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Now that I&amp;#8217;m &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/0-to-art-in-two-weeks&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;receiving real art&lt;/a&gt; for my game, I thought it would be a good time to learn about memory usage and limits. This was also prompted by my current level running at 55-60MB before any gameplay action or characters loaded on screen. That memory usage seemed a bit high, so I decided this was an issue that I needed to &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=2o1U2pWcR34&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;delve into&lt;/a&gt;. In hindsight, most of this is basic to an experienced game developer, but I found the process to be quite fun. You can just read my lessons learned below if you don&amp;#8217;t want to follow my detective work.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Z-Index by Screen Coordinates</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/18/handling-z-index-by-screen-coordinates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 14:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/18/handling-z-index-by-screen-coordinates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One problem that I ran into with my game was that my characters and images were not being properly z-indexed. For example, the dwarf in the image below looks like he&amp;#8217;s pasted on top of the tree, even though his position on the map suggests he should be behind the tree.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Corona</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/22/getting-started-with-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 17:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/22/getting-started-with-corona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working on my game for about three months now and I feel like I&amp;#8217;m in a pretty good spot. I have a good grasp of LUA and the Corona SDK and my problems are more focused on what type of game to make and not how to make a game. I&amp;#8217;ve spent a lot of time reading documentation and taking tutorials and I want to share the resources that helped me get started with any fellow beginners out there.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Image Selection with Corona and Texture Packer</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/30/dynamic-image-selection-with-corona-and-texture-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 15:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/30/dynamic-image-selection-with-corona-and-texture-packer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most mobile apps are developed to run across multiple devices, which means developers have to account for multiple screen resolutions. Image scaling is an important part of multi-device support because you want to use higher resolution images on modern, high-res devices, while using lower resolution images on low-res devices. That saves memory on the low-res devices while maximizing all of the pixel density goodness on the high-res devices. Lucky for Corona SDK developers, Corona makes image scaling a breeze with their &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.coronalabs.com/guide/basics/configSettings/#dynamic-image-selection&#34;&gt;dynamic image selection&lt;/a&gt; feature.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Bars and Taking Damage in Corona SDK</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/24/health-bars-and-taking-damage-in-corona-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 17:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/24/health-bars-and-taking-damage-in-corona-sdk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s common to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/health-display-roundup&#34;&gt;health bars attached to a characters&lt;/a&gt; in video games, and in this tutorial I explain how that can easily be accomplished in Corona SDK. And as an added bonus, the health bar also updates as the character takes damage.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Movement Grid Display Techniques</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/18/10-unique-movement-grid-display-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 16:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/18/10-unique-movement-grid-display-techniques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An easy way to add distinction and flavor to your game is to make seemingly standard concepts into &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/health-display-roundup&#34;&gt;unique game art&lt;/a&gt;. For example, two visual elements that pretty much all turn based tactical games contain are a means of displaying how far character can move and what enemies are within attack range. It would be easy to just make some squares green and others red, but you&amp;#8217;d be missing an opportunity to add a little polish to your game. To visually understand what I&amp;#8217;m talking about, here are screenshots of games that implement standard concepts in unique ways.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Challenges You May Encounter While Porting Your SpriteKit Game to Swift</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/18/challenges-you-may-encounter-while-porting-your-spritekit-game-to-swift/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 16:20:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/18/challenges-you-may-encounter-while-porting-your-spritekit-game-to-swift/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The introduction of &lt;a href=&#34;https://developer.apple.com/swift/&#34;&gt;Swift&lt;/a&gt; comes at a perfect time for me. I’ve been working on a SpriteKit game in Objective-C for 10 weeks now, and some of the code is definitely in need of refactoring. Refactoring is known to be tedious, so being able to learn a new language during the process is a plus. I’ve been taking notes of any challenge I’ve come across during the conversion.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isometric Tiles and Pathfinding with Corona</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/03/isometric-tiles-and-pathfinding-with-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/03/isometric-tiles-and-pathfinding-with-corona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I previously wrote a tutorial on how to create a square grid and &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/pathfinding-in-corona-with-jumper-and-a-star&#34;&gt;implement pathfinding with Corona SDK&lt;/a&gt; and the Jumper library, but now we&amp;#8217;re going to take things up a notch and do the same thing on an isometric grid. Isometric grids use rhombus, or diamond shaped tiles, as opposed to square tiles. The introduction of angled tiles adds the perception of depth and can dramatically change the visuals of your game without adding much complexity to your code.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>First Look at SKLightNode in iOS8</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/03/first-look-at-sklightnode-in-ios8/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 17:24:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/03/first-look-at-sklightnode-in-ios8/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lighting effects were curiously missing from SpriteKit in iOS7, so I&amp;#8217;m happy to see them appear in iOS8. Here&amp;#8217;s a quick look at what you can expect from the light source / raycasting implementation.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Turn Based Game Projection Techniques</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/21/common-turn-based-game-projection-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 16:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/21/common-turn-based-game-projection-techniques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple commonly used projection techniques for turn based video games are &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthographic_projection&#34;&gt;orthographic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isometric_projection&#34;&gt;isometric&lt;/a&gt; projection. I&amp;#8217;m in the process of figuring out which technique I&amp;#8217;ll be using for my tactics game and I&amp;#8217;ve been looking into the pros and cons of each method and how they&amp;#8217;ve been used in previous games. Here&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;ve discovered so far.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Learning Sprite Kit by Example</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/15/learning-sprite-kit-by-example/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2014 14:13:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/15/learning-sprite-kit-by-example/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I hated school. I hate technical books. Generally, I feel like I can learn faster with the unstoppable trio of myself, Google and wonderful online communities. The trouble with game development is I don&amp;#8217;t know what questions to ask. In web development, I can search how to make two elements sit next to each other and find what I&amp;#8217;m looking for. In game development, I wouldn&amp;#8217;t have looked for a finite state machine, much less double dispatch for physics. I may be late to the party compared to other developers, but I&amp;#8217;m finding myself humbled by both books and open source projects that are extremely well crafted.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathfinding in Corona with Jumper and A Star</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/24/pathfinding-in-corona-with-jumper-and-a-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 15:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/24/pathfinding-in-corona-with-jumper-and-a-star/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re making a grid based game and you need a character to move from point A to point B while avoiding obstacles, then you&amp;#8217;re going to need some type of pathfinding. Luckily for us, Roland Yonaba utilized the power of A Star, a popular pathfinding algorithm, and made it even better with his open source Jumper library. Visually, what we&amp;#8217;re trying to accomplish looks a little something like:
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Tips from The App Store Playbook</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/22/4-tips-from-the-app-store-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 16:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/22/4-tips-from-the-app-store-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently bought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-App-Store-Playbook-Successful-ebook/dp/B009P1YPGK&#34;&gt;The App Store Playbook&lt;/a&gt;, written by Shane Lee, because &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hunters-2/id489463556?mt=8&#34;&gt;Hunters&lt;/a&gt; was highlighted and it&amp;#8217;s one of my favorite iPad games. Fortunately for me, the other 9 interviews were all solid, and I came away with some good indie game dev tips that I thought I&amp;#8217;d share.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling zPosition in a 2.5d World</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/21/handling-zposition-in-a-2-5d-world/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 15:28:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/21/handling-zposition-in-a-2-5d-world/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Not surprisingly, dealing with zPosition in a 2.5d game is about as complicated as everything else in game development &amp;#8212; it will be harder to handle than you think it should be. For example, how should you handle moving a sprite from behind a tree to in front of a tree in perceived depth. While the initial drawing of objects is straightforward, things become tricky once they start moving around. Let&amp;#8217;s take a look at how I&amp;#8217;m approaching zPosition in my Sprite Kit game.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating Sprites from a Texture Packer Image</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/10/animating-sprites-from-a-texture-packer-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 16:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/10/animating-sprites-from-a-texture-packer-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting with animation and recently ran into a little trouble with spritesheets, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeandweb.com/texturepacker&#34;&gt;TexturePacker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/&#34;&gt;Corona SDK&lt;/a&gt; and animation. The problem started when I wanted to animate &lt;a href=&#34;http://opengameart.org/content/700-sprites&#34;&gt;some sprites&lt;/a&gt; from opengameart.org. The download included 89 animation sequences and each animation contained 8 individual character sprites, which looked like:
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Game design books for $80.80</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/3-game-design-books-for-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/3-game-design-books-for-80/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;#8217;d kick this contest off by purchasing a little bed time reading material. I want to start prototyping games as soon as possible, so hopefully a few books on game theory and design will help me to avoid some of the mistakes beginners make.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>