<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Sirchris on Battle of Brothers</title>
    <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/categories/sirchris/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Sirchris on Battle of Brothers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 17:07:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://battleofbrothers.com/categories/sirchris/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Slow and Steady</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/09/16/slow-and-steady/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Sep 2015 17:07:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/09/16/slow-and-steady/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’ve been able to get a bunch done in the last month and I’m getting closer and closer to my short-term goal of having a playable first 4 levels. This update includes new character animations, new attack icons, an updated character select screen, intro movie updates, and pinch/zoom functionality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What makes a game fun?</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/08/06/what-makes-a-game-fun/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Aug 2015 20:15:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/08/06/what-makes-a-game-fun/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m at the point of development where I feel I have a rough, yet playable, version of the game’s core functionality. I’ve built the intro, menu system, world map, battle maps, and character selection. I’ve created a playable, yet not very fun, game. And that leads me to my next big challenge which is to make the game fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character Creation</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/07/09/character-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jul 2015 19:08:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/07/09/character-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After working on the intro, world map, and combat layer, it was time to work on the character selection screen. My short-term goal is to have 4 playable levels and the only major missing piece is the functionality to manage your heroes. Everything is still in a bit of a rough state, but here’s a look at what I have so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sound and Music</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/06/10/sound-and-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jun 2015 13:19:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/06/10/sound-and-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the last update I demoed the &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/the-battlefield-ui&#34;&gt;latest version of the game’s battle layer&lt;/a&gt; and I&amp;#8217;m comfortable with how that part of the game is progressing. There are still bugs to squish and polish to add, but now that I’m confident in the game’s art, animation, and general flow, it’s time to give audio some love. I’ve contracted the pros to help me out in this area, and with their help the game has gotten some fantastic ear candy. Here’s a look at the latest build with the new audio enhancements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Battlefield UI</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/05/27/the-battlefield-ui/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2015 17:40:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/05/27/the-battlefield-ui/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Many of my UI elements have been pretty ugly so far, but those days are soon coming to an end. I’ve now received pretty much all of the game’s artwork and in the last few weeks I started implementing the UI portion of that work. There’s still plenty of polish to add, but here’s a look at the battlefield UI in its current state.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Very Basic Game</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/28/a-very-basic-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Apr 2015 18:50:52 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/28/a-very-basic-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Even though I &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/one-year-later-late-and-over-budget&#34;&gt;missed my goal&lt;/a&gt; of releasing a game after a year of development, I still have a pretty solid foundation to build upon. And by foundation I mean an intro video, start screen, working world map, and very basic, yet playable battlefields. There’s still a lot of work to do, but here’s a look at those key foundation areas put together in the form of a simple game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Year Later – Late and Over Budget</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/08/one-year-later-late-and-over-budget/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Apr 2015 17:37:55 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/08/one-year-later-late-and-over-budget/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Today marks the one year anniversary of our &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com&#34;&gt;game development competition&lt;/a&gt;, so I can now safely say that the game will be late. Not only will the game be late, but I&amp;#8217;m also about &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/budget&#34;&gt;2k over budget&lt;/a&gt;. If you had asked me a year ago if I would be disappointed about being late and over budget, I would have absolutely said yes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$1500 on Music</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/1500-on-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 20:02:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/1500-on-music/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve entered into a contract with &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brendonwilliams.com&#34;&gt;Brendon Williams&lt;/a&gt; to compose the game&amp;#8217;s music. He&amp;#8217;ll be doing everything from intro music, battle music, world map music, and any other types of music that come up. Brendon recently started with the music for the intro movie and it&amp;#8217;s &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oChbnCv1H1k&#34;&gt;sounding awesome&lt;/a&gt;.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$7323 on Animations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/7323-on-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 20:00:14 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/7323-on-animations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve received a bunch of animations over the last few months and you can see a lot of them over at &lt;a href=&#34;https://vimeo.com/dualbo&#34;&gt;Dualbo&amp;#8217;s Vimeo Site&lt;/a&gt; and in &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/knights-ninjas-and-wizards&#34;&gt;my status updates&lt;/a&gt;. I&amp;#8217;ve received 12 of the 18 characters that will be in the game, so we&amp;#8217;re two-thirds there. I think this payment has officially put my game over budget, but that&amp;#8217;s how these things go sometimes. The good news is that the animations are awesome and worth every penny.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$2500 on Illustrations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/2500-on-illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 19:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/2500-on-illustrations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This expense wasn&amp;#8217;t a lump sum payment, but 4 payments made over the course of a couple months. I&amp;#8217;m extended the original contract with the illustrator because the game has more artwork than I originally anticipated. The following illustrations were done for this update:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating a Path Using Image Masking</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/animating-a-path-using-image-masking/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Apr 2015 18:40:23 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/04/06/animating-a-path-using-image-masking/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently found myself wanting to animate a character&amp;#8217;s progress path and initially I thought I would do this by creating multiple animation frames, much like a sprite. After a bit of frustration, trial and error, I realized that creating an image mask was a more efficient and effective method.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To give you an example of what I was trying to accomplish, here is a picture of a portion of my game&amp;#8217;s world map. The yellow and line is the path that my character takes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Music &amp; Memory</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/03/31/music-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2015 17:17:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/03/31/music-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I’m happy to report that I’ve received the first 30 seconds of game music and that my ears are happy with what they&amp;#8217;re hearing. It’s amazing what a little sound can do to the intro video and I can’t wait to see how the future music adds more depth to the game. I’ve also continued to experiment with some memory concerns and making scene transitions as smooth as possible. That’s required a bit of a re-write, but the game is heavy on texture memory usage, so it’s important to tackle this issue sooner than later.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Another Shot at the Intro Video</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/03/17/another-shot-at-the-intro-video/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Mar 2015 14:40:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/03/17/another-shot-at-the-intro-video/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I said I wouldn’t do it, but I couldn’t help myself and took another crack at the intro video. The main practical reason is because the game’s music is being composed, and it kind of all derives from the intro song. The main impractical reason is because I hated the first video and couldn’t help myself from trying again. Here’s look at the second attempt.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intro Video, Artwork, and Audio</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/03/03/intro-video-artwork-and-audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Mar 2015 16:21:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/03/03/intro-video-artwork-and-audio/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I have a lot to share this time around, including icons, character animations, splash screens, world map animations, music and sound, and cut scenes. But the biggest achievement over the last two weeks was completing the first take of the game’s intro video, which you can see below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Knights, Ninjas, and Wizards</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/02/16/knights-ninjas-and-wizards/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Feb 2015 14:16:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/02/16/knights-ninjas-and-wizards/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Knights, Ninjas, and Wizards… If that title didn’t get you hooked, then you’re in the wrong place! I added some great sprites to the game in the last two weeks, but a man can only play with sprite sheets so long before he loses his sanity. I didn’t want to lose my sanity, so I also worked on my intro scenes in an attempt to regain control of my mind. I’m really happy with how everything is turning out so far, and you can see what I have so far after a quick word from our sponsors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fights, cut scenes, and texture memory</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/02/04/fights-cut-scenes-and-texture-memory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Feb 2015 16:15:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/02/04/fights-cut-scenes-and-texture-memory/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The good news is that I’ve received a ton of artwork over the last two weeks. The bad news is that I can only demo a small portion of it because there just isn’t enough time to get it all into the game. That’s a good problem to have, though, and what I can show you is some pretty cool cut scenes, some character animations, and this sweet footage of a knight putting the beat down on an evil ogre.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Character Creation Process</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/27/the-character-creation-process/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Jan 2015 15:15:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/27/the-character-creation-process/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the most enjoyable parts of the game development process so far has been creating characters. Using my imagination to discover how they look, what abilities they have, where they&amp;#8217;re from, and how they talk is immensely satisfying. Largely due to the efforts of the illustrator and animator I&amp;#8217;m contracting, the first character of the game was just fully completed. I&amp;#8217;m extremely happy with the outcome and thought I&amp;#8217;d share with you the process of how he came to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Barbarian Smash!</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/20/barbarian-smash/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Jan 2015 14:17:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/20/barbarian-smash/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I feel like I made some really solid progress for the first time in a while, and I have some exciting stuff to share. A ton of little things were done, but the big accomplishments are the implementation of some awesome attack animations, battlefield animations, and world map animations. I also received some great new artwork and I gave my marketing efforts some much-needed love.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=y6cgpwZo6Ck&amp;amp;list=UU9mKr14Czu1VWN6jYAGeqHA&#34;&gt;view all of this week&amp;#8217;s updates&lt;/a&gt; with added commentary on YouTube or continue reading for a quick breakdown of each section.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Transitioning an Image but Not a Mask in Corona SDK</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/transitioning-an-image-but-not-a-mask-in-corona-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Jan 2015 14:09:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/transitioning-an-image-but-not-a-mask-in-corona-sdk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was recently playing around with image masking, and I wanted to transition the mask so that the image behind it gradually appeared on screen. Unfortunately, Corona doesn&amp;#8217;t allow you to transition masks, but after &lt;a href=&#34;http://forums.coronalabs.com/topic/34774-moving-image-but-not-mask/&#34;&gt;doing a little research&lt;/a&gt; I learned that you can use groups to transition the image behind the mask. Here&amp;#8217;s an example to see what I&amp;#8217;m talking about.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character Dialogue and Scripted Scenes</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/06/character-dialogue-and-scripted-scenes/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jan 2015 16:43:26 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2015/01/06/character-dialogue-and-scripted-scenes/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;With the holidays upon us, I wasn&amp;#8217;t able to get much done over the last couple of weeks. But when I did get the chance to work, I made it count. I&amp;#8217;ve been putting off character dialogue and scripted scenes for a while now, but I&amp;#8217;m happy to say the framework to achieve that is now in place. Here is a brief example of a couple of characters engaging in a well written scripted scene, full of deception, intrigue, and suspense.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animations!</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/12/04/animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2014 20:20:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/12/04/animations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s been a little while since the last status update, due to the holidays and a mean case of strep, but I have some pretty cool stuff to share. I had hoped to add the functionality for dialogue into the game, but my animator got back to me with some awesome animations and I just couldn&amp;#8217;t wait to implement them. So here&amp;#8217;s a look at 4 of the hero character animations hot off the assembly line.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Visual Progress</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/11/12/visual-progress/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Nov 2014 17:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/11/12/visual-progress/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I really enjoyed working on the game over the last few weeks because pretty much everything I did resulted in visual progress. Adding code and manipulating JSON files is good and dandy, but programming is a lot more exciting when I&amp;#8217;m working on something that my family and friends can visually experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Core Improvement</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/10/22/core-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 22 Oct 2014 17:50:10 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/10/22/core-improvement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As planned after the last update, I was able to add scene management, loading and saving functionality, and the ability to view the game on a physical device. There are also some pretty cool new battleground maps and my first character sprite .png animation to check out below.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$588 on Corona SDK Pro Subscription</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/10/20/588-on-corona-sdk-pro-subscription/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Oct 2014 13:03:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/10/20/588-on-corona-sdk-pro-subscription/</guid>
      <description>I was using Corona&amp;#8217;s free product for awhile, but I decided to upgrade to the pro subscription once I continuously encounter bugs with live builds on the free trial. My game is still a ways off from completion, and I wish I could have used the free trial problem free for a little bit longer, but I knew I&amp;#8217;d have to fork up the money eventually.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarter 2 Game Development Stats</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/10/08/quarter-2-game-development-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 13:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/10/08/quarter-2-game-development-stats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished up my second quarter of game development and have fresh round of statistics to share with you all. Numbers never lie and the numbers say that while my productivity stayed consistent, less time was spent on programming and more was spent on game design. My marketing efforts stayed about the same and both the blog and Twitter readership grew at a slow and steady rate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Continuous Improvement</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/30/continuous-improvement/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Sep 2014 19:37:01 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/30/continuous-improvement/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As planned, I was able to continue programming over the last two weeks and add some more features and a new character to the demo. I also spent a little time working on some new character concepts, battlegrounds, and animation preparation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Level Design – Concept to Creation</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/24/level-design-concept-to-creation/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Sep 2014 12:52:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/24/level-design-concept-to-creation/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working on level design with an illustrator for the last couple weeks and things are really moving along nicely. What once took about 3 days of work is now condensed down into almost a day. We have 5 or so levels knocked out at this stage and I thought I&amp;#8217;d share the process on how they come to life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Back to Programming</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/17/back-to-programming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Sep 2014 13:59:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/17/back-to-programming/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;For the first time in what feels like forever, I was able to get back into actually programming. I had no idea that hiring artists, researching art direction, building design documents, and working with contractors would take so much time, but it does. I can understand why studios have art directors and game designers because those two jobs take up just as much time as programming. Anyways, I was able to spend a full week programming, and here is a video update on where the game is at:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$3733 on Illustrations and Animations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/09/3733-on-illustrations-and-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2014 19:18:04 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/09/3733-on-illustrations-and-animations/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been working with the an illustrator and animator for a few weeks now they&amp;#8217;ve produced the world map, multiple battlefield maps, concept characters, character turnarounds, and 2 animated characters (semi produced). I&amp;#8217;m pretty close to staying on budget so far, but I can see how both artists could end up costing a bit more than I originally thought.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Character and Level Design</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/03/character-and-level-design/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2014 15:58:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/09/03/character-and-level-design/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I had just started working with an illustrator when I last left off, and most of my time over the last two weeks was spent designing some pretty cool characters and battlefields. I was also able to contract a character animator, who is now working on the game&amp;#8217;s first character animations.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$96 on Trial Animations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/96-on-trial-animations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 14:57:34 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/96-on-trial-animations/</guid>
      <description>I had a couple of animators create test animations off of one of my character concepts just to see if their style fit what I have in mind for the game. Both animators were able to mock up a 3D animation in about 3 hours. Neither of the trial animators was the right fit for me this time around, but I&amp;#8217;ll hold onto their contact information for the future.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$800 on Illustrations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/800-on-illustrations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 14:24:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/800-on-illustrations/</guid>
      <description>I found an illustrator for my game, and he started out by creating some character concepts and a couple of battlefield scenes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$200 on Behance</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/200-on-behance/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2014 14:21:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/27/200-on-behance/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;#8217;ve been looking for an animator and the three methods of recruitment that I used were making a blog post, reaching out to people I admired on Carbonmade, and paying for a job listing on Behance. I received 52 applications within 5 days and ended up finding the right man for the job through Behance. If he works out, then this was $200 well spent.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Designing Backgrounds for Multiple Aspect Ratios and Corona’s Config.lua</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/26/designing-backgrounds-for-multiple-aspect-ratios-and-coronas-config-lua/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2014 13:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/26/designing-backgrounds-for-multiple-aspect-ratios-and-coronas-config-lua/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the reasons I chose Corona SDK as my development platform was because they support many devices across many platforms. But mo&amp;#8217; devices means mo&amp;#8217; problems, and one of those problems is creating artwork that scales across all devices.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Found an Illustrator</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/20/found-an-illustrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Aug 2014 14:40:56 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/20/found-an-illustrator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I left off last time, I was working with an illustrator to see if he could create the style of art I hope to use in my game. I&amp;#8217;m happy to say that he exceeded my expectations and will be playing a large role in the game&amp;#8217;s development. In addition to formally contracting the artist, I spent a little time playing with game mechanics and a lot of time preparing for the art that&amp;#8217;s about to come rolling in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>$325 on Illustrator Trial Run</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/18/325-on-illustrator-trial-run/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 15:55:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/18/325-on-illustrator-trial-run/</guid>
      <description>I made a list of illustrators who I planned on contacting for trial illustrations, but I lucked out by having Scott Pellico go first. Scott illustrated a piece of my world map as a trial to see if his style was a fit for the world I&amp;#8217;d like to create. He nailed it and I&amp;#8217;m lucky to have found a quality illustrator on the first go.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Handling Z-Index by Screen Coordinates</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/18/handling-z-index-by-screen-coordinates/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Aug 2014 14:48:27 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/18/handling-z-index-by-screen-coordinates/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One problem that I ran into with my game was that my characters and images were not being properly z-indexed. For example, the dwarf in the image below looks like he&amp;#8217;s pasted on top of the tree, even though his position on the map suggests he should be behind the tree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Start of My Game</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/05/the-start-of-my-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Aug 2014 17:29:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/08/05/the-start-of-my-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Up until this update, everything that I did was basically learning and testing basic concepts that could be applied to many types of turn based games. Characters moved, attacked, died, etc. I&amp;#8217;ve known that I wanted to make a turn based game, but I didn&amp;#8217;t know exactly what I was going to build. That all changed this time around, because over the last two weeks I decided what game I want to build, created an art design document, and contracted an illustrator to draw preliminary sketches.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What I’m Looking for in an Illustrator</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/31/what-im-looking-for-in-an-illustrator/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 31 Jul 2014 15:00:24 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/31/what-im-looking-for-in-an-illustrator/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m in the process of contracting an illustrator and so far I&amp;#8217;ve looked at more profiles on &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.deviantart.com&#34;&gt;deviantART&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.behance.net&#34;&gt;Behance&lt;/a&gt; than I can remember. I thought this would be an easy process, but I&amp;#8217;ve never worked with an illustrator before and I never realized how many variables would come into play when searching for the right person. I know I won&amp;#8217;t find everything I&amp;#8217;m looking for, but here are some of the variables I&amp;#8217;m taking into consideration while looking for the right person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting Started with Corona</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/22/getting-started-with-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2014 17:37:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/22/getting-started-with-corona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been working on my game for about three months now and I feel like I&amp;#8217;m in a pretty good spot. I have a good grasp of LUA and the Corona SDK and my problems are more focused on what type of game to make and not how to make a game. I&amp;#8217;ve spent a lot of time reading documentation and taking tutorials and I want to share the resources that helped me get started with any fellow beginners out there.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring of Character Creation Code</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/21/refactoring-of-character-creation-code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Jul 2014 16:37:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/21/refactoring-of-character-creation-code/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After the last update, I had plans to build out the HUD and add new attack actions to my characters. I added a new attack action to the archer and was feeling excited about all the new awesomeness about to go into my game. Unfortunately, my excitement was short-lived because I quickly realized that my code needed to be refactored before adding new action functionality to all my characters. Warning: This article gets technical.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Months of Game Development Statistics</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/09/3-months-of-game-development-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 18:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/07/09/3-months-of-game-development-statistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m hoping make my game development process transparent as possible, so on a quarterly basis I plan to publish some figures related to productivity, marketing, code count, and anything else that may be relevant to other game developers out there. So without further ado, here are some stats related to my first three months of game development.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Dynamic Image Selection with Corona and Texture Packer</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/30/dynamic-image-selection-with-corona-and-texture-packer/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 15:26:31 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/30/dynamic-image-selection-with-corona-and-texture-packer/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Most mobile apps are developed to run across multiple devices, which means developers have to account for multiple screen resolutions. Image scaling is an important part of multi-device support because you want to use higher resolution images on modern, high-res devices, while using lower resolution images on low-res devices. That saves memory on the low-res devices while maximizing all of the pixel density goodness on the high-res devices. Lucky for Corona SDK developers, Corona makes image scaling a breeze with their &lt;a href=&#34;http://docs.coronalabs.com/guide/basics/configSettings/#dynamic-image-selection&#34;&gt;dynamic image selection&lt;/a&gt; feature.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multi-Device Support and HUD Elements</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/30/multi-device-support-and-hud-elements/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Jun 2014 15:25:12 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/30/multi-device-support-and-hud-elements/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This update was delayed by a week because I took a &amp;#8220;&lt;a href=&#34;http://www.ragnartrail.com/locations/appalachians-wv&#34;&gt;vacation&lt;/a&gt;&amp;#8220;, but I&amp;#8217;m back in action and hard at work again. After the last update I had some concerns about making my game work across multiple devices, but I&amp;#8217;m happy to say that Corona makes multi-device support pretty easy. It was actually so easy that I was not only able to make my prototype work across multiple devices, but I also had time to start adding some basic HUD elements to the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Bars and Taking Damage in Corona SDK</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/24/health-bars-and-taking-damage-in-corona-sdk/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Jun 2014 17:30:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/24/health-bars-and-taking-damage-in-corona-sdk/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s common to see &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/health-display-roundup&#34;&gt;health bars attached to a characters&lt;/a&gt; in video games, and in this tutorial I explain how that can easily be accomplished in Corona SDK. And as an added bonus, the health bar also updates as the character takes damage.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>10 Movement Grid Display Techniques</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/18/10-unique-movement-grid-display-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2014 16:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/18/10-unique-movement-grid-display-techniques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;An easy way to add distinction and flavor to your game is to make seemingly standard concepts into &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/health-display-roundup&#34;&gt;unique game art&lt;/a&gt;. For example, two visual elements that pretty much all turn based tactical games contain are a means of displaying how far character can move and what enemies are within attack range. It would be easy to just make some squares green and others red, but you&amp;#8217;d be missing an opportunity to add a little polish to your game. To visually understand what I&amp;#8217;m talking about, here are screenshots of games that implement standard concepts in unique ways.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Zombies, Archers, and Dwarfs! Oh My!</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/10/zombies-archers-and-dwarfs-oh-my/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 10 Jun 2014 16:19:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/10/zombies-archers-and-dwarfs-oh-my/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve added a lot of pretty cool changes to my prototype in the last two weeks, including new characters, attack animations, directional movement, death animations, and sound effects. The game is still a very rough prototype, but as you can see in the video below, I&amp;#8217;m now able to actually play a complete level from start to finish.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Isometric Tiles and Pathfinding with Corona</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/03/isometric-tiles-and-pathfinding-with-corona/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Jun 2014 17:43:32 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/06/03/isometric-tiles-and-pathfinding-with-corona/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I previously wrote a tutorial on how to create a square grid and &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/pathfinding-in-corona-with-jumper-and-a-star&#34;&gt;implement pathfinding with Corona SDK&lt;/a&gt; and the Jumper library, but now we&amp;#8217;re going to take things up a notch and do the same thing on an isometric grid. Isometric grids use rhombus, or diamond shaped tiles, as opposed to square tiles. The introduction of angled tiles adds the perception of depth and can dramatically change the visuals of your game without adding much complexity to your code.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Little Perspective</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/27/a-little-perspective/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 15:40:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/27/a-little-perspective/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was really excited after the last update because I felt like the foundation of my code was relatively solid and the core game mechanics were working. With that core work out of the way, I was free to focus on polishing what I had built and thinking about what type of game I ultimately want to build. In the last 2 weeks I was able to fix a bunch of bugs, add obstacles, add art, and switch the camera point of view. Add all of those together and you get a game that&amp;#8217;s starting to look pretty sweet in my unbiased opinion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Common Turn Based Game Projection Techniques</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/21/common-turn-based-game-projection-techniques/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 May 2014 16:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/21/common-turn-based-game-projection-techniques/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A couple commonly used projection techniques for turn based video games are &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Orthographic_projection&#34;&gt;orthographic&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Isometric_projection&#34;&gt;isometric&lt;/a&gt; projection. I&amp;#8217;m in the process of figuring out which technique I&amp;#8217;ll be using for my tactics game and I&amp;#8217;ve been looking into the pros and cons of each method and how they&amp;#8217;ve been used in previous games. Here&amp;#8217;s what I&amp;#8217;ve discovered so far.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Beginning of a Game</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/12/the-beginning-of-a-game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 May 2014 18:55:50 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/12/the-beginning-of-a-game/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m a little over a month into my game now and I feel like I finally have something that resembles what will one day be a playable game. When I left off last time, I was hoping to add some AI to the game, and I&amp;#8217;m happy to report that the AI system wasn&amp;#8217;t as hard as I had originally feared. In the last two weeks, I was able to add archer and mage characters to the game and also give the enemy characters some intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To see where I&amp;#8217;m out, check out the following video.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health Display Roundup</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/05/health-display-roundup/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 05 May 2014 16:59:16 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/05/05/health-display-roundup/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Visually displaying a character&amp;#8217;s health has been around for over 30 years and continues to be a mainstay of video games. From Zelda to Starcraft, these small graphics play a large role in how games are played and how information is communicated. The turn based game I&amp;#8217;m working on will include health bars, so I&amp;#8217;ve been looking into how other successful games have given their characters life. Here is a quick roundup of some of the more popular techniques I&amp;#8217;ve come across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactoring</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/28/refactoring/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2014 18:24:53 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/28/refactoring/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When I left off two weeks ago, I had the goal of adding some bad guys to fight my valiant knight. The good news is that those bad guys can now be seen and attacked, but the bad news is that for every step forward, I&amp;#8217;ve had to take about 0.9 steps back. If learning was the name of the game before my first update, refactoring is the name of the game this time around. I knew there was going to be a price to pay for plunging into my game without much thought given to organization and structure, and it was time to pay the piper.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But in an effort to stay positive about game development, let&amp;#8217;s celebrate the visual progress I&amp;#8217;ve made.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pathfinding in Corona with Jumper and A Star</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/24/pathfinding-in-corona-with-jumper-and-a-star/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 24 Apr 2014 15:57:28 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/24/pathfinding-in-corona-with-jumper-and-a-star/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;#8217;re making a grid based game and you need a character to move from point A to point B while avoiding obstacles, then you&amp;#8217;re going to need some type of pathfinding. Luckily for us, Roland Yonaba utilized the power of A Star, a popular pathfinding algorithm, and made it even better with his open source Jumper library. Visually, what we&amp;#8217;re trying to accomplish looks a little something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Tips from The App Store Playbook</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/22/4-tips-from-the-app-store-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 16:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/22/4-tips-from-the-app-store-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently bought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-App-Store-Playbook-Successful-ebook/dp/B009P1YPGK&#34;&gt;The App Store Playbook&lt;/a&gt;, written by Shane Lee, because &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hunters-2/id489463556?mt=8&#34;&gt;Hunters&lt;/a&gt; was highlighted and it&amp;#8217;s one of my favorite iPad games. Fortunately for me, the other 9 interviews were all solid, and I came away with some good indie game dev tips that I thought I&amp;#8217;d share.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Texture Packer and Physics Editor for $50</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/18/texture-packer-and-physics-editor-for-50/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2014 19:00:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/18/texture-packer-and-physics-editor-for-50/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I could avoid throwing down any cash for sprite sheet development, but I finally broke down and purchased &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.codeandweb.com&#34;&gt;Texture Packer&lt;/a&gt;. They just make sprite sheet creation too easy, and the tool spits out exactly what the Corona SDK needs to render and scale sprites.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beginnings</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/14/beginnings/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2014 17:48:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/14/beginnings/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m two weeks into game development and I&amp;#8217;ve realized that making a game will require a lot of learning and hard work, and this is going to be a lot of fun. I know so little about game development that it&amp;#8217;s difficult to even know where to start. What should be a seemingly simple task, like animating and moving a sprite, can be challenging due to amateur hour mistakes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Animating Sprites from a Texture Packer Image</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/10/animating-sprites-from-a-texture-packer-image/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 16:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/10/animating-sprites-from-a-texture-packer-image/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve been experimenting with animation and recently ran into a little trouble with spritesheets, &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.codeandweb.com/texturepacker&#34;&gt;TexturePacker&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;a href=&#34;http://coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/&#34;&gt;Corona SDK&lt;/a&gt; and animation. The problem started when I wanted to animate &lt;a href=&#34;http://opengameart.org/content/700-sprites&#34;&gt;some sprites&lt;/a&gt; from opengameart.org. The download included 89 animation sequences and each animation contained 8 individual character sprites, which looked like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Chose the Corona SDK over Sprite Kit, Unity, or Cocos2d-x</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/07/why-i-chose-the-corona-sdk-over-sprite-kit-unity-or-cocos2d-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 15:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/04/07/why-i-chose-the-corona-sdk-over-sprite-kit-unity-or-cocos2d-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve spent the last couple of weeks testing out different 2d game development frameworks, and I&amp;#8217;ve decided that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/&#34;&gt;Corona SDK&lt;/a&gt; is the tool for me. I was hoping there would be a standout framework that could make basic 2d games much better than the others, but I feel they each have pros and cons and they can all make games just fine. What it really comes down to is what makes me comfortable and excited about game development. I&amp;#8217;m not qualified to list out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raywenderlich.com/67585/cocos2d-vs-sprite-kit-vs-unity-2d-tech-talk-video&#34;&gt;pros and cons of each environment&lt;/a&gt;, since I&amp;#8217;ve been developing games for all of two weeks, but I can tell you why Corona won my business.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The official winner of this competition (and bragging rights) is going to be the brother whose game makes the most money, but all won&amp;#8217;t be lost if I come closer to my end goal of becoming a game developer. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/quotes/b/brucelee385747.html&#34;&gt;Bruce Lee&lt;/a&gt; said that, &amp;#8220;a goal is not always meant to be reached, it often serves simply as something to aim at&amp;#8221;, and here are the targets that I&amp;#8217;ve set out to hit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Blog</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/why-i-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/why-i-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Ryan and I decided to hold this competition, the first thing we did was create this blog. It was tempting test game development frameworks, prototype, or do anything actually related to game development, but we know first hand the benefits of blogging on both yourself and your product. Blogging does cut into precious development time, but I believe the benefits outweigh the costs for a number of reasons.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m a n00b</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/im-a-n00b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/im-a-n00b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All journeys have beginnings and today is where my journey starts. While I might not be as useless as the n00b &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wizards.com/Magic/tcg/newtomagic.aspx&#34;&gt;MTG&lt;/a&gt; card above, I do lack most of the skills required to build a video game. Advancing from beginner to competent game developer will be a difficult task, but I&amp;#8217;m hoping that&amp;#8217;s where this quest leads.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Game design books for $80.80</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/3-game-design-books-for-80/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:50:40 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/3-game-design-books-for-80/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I thought I&amp;#8217;d kick this contest off by purchasing a little bed time reading material. I want to start prototyping games as soon as possible, so hopefully a few books on game theory and design will help me to avoid some of the mistakes beginners make.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Site!</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/welcome-to-the-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/2014/03/26/welcome-to-the-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there, I&amp;#8217;m Chris and welcome to my game development blog. In case you came directly to this site and not through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com&#34;&gt;splash page&lt;/a&gt;, let me give you a quick intro as to what&amp;#8217;s going on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>