<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Thoughts on Battle of Brothers</title>
    <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/tags/thoughts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Thoughts on Battle of Brothers</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 16:35:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://battleofbrothers.com/tags/thoughts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>My Take on Health Bars</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/my-take-on-health-bars/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 12 Jan 2015 16:35:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/my-take-on-health-bars/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Health indicators are found in almost every game. As Chris pointed out, they come in a &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/health-display-roundup&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;variety of shapes and sizes&lt;/a&gt;. When it became time to think about them in my game, I wanted to add something that was functional, but also unique or interesting in some way.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quarter 2 Game Development Stats</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/quarter-2-game-development-stats/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2014 13:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/quarter-2-game-development-stats/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I just finished up my second quarter of game development and have fresh round of statistics to share with you all. Numbers never lie and the numbers say that while my productivity stayed consistent, less time was spent on programming and more was spent on game design. My marketing efforts stayed about the same and both the blog and Twitter readership grew at a slow and steady rate.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Experiences Searching for an Artist</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/my-experiences-searching-for-an-artist/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2014 17:19:47 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/my-experiences-searching-for-an-artist/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Finding an artist has been my biggest fear since this competition started. There are so many things that could go wrong when you have to depend on someone you don&amp;#8217;t know to contribute a third or more to your project. The style may not be a match, they could leave half way through the project, the budget estimations may be way off &amp;#8212; the list goes on and on. I must say though, I&amp;#8217;ve gained confidence in art contractors in the two weeks I&amp;#8217;ve been speaking with them. I thought I would share some of my notes.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Stats From the First Quarter</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/stats-from-the-first-quarter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 18:41:59 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/stats-from-the-first-quarter/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;It&amp;#8217;s hard to believe that we&amp;#8217;re already 3 months into the competition. My first quarter of game development consisted of many &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/the-shaping-of-a-game&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;highs&lt;/a&gt; and &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/its-not-all-sunshine-and-rainbows&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;lows&lt;/a&gt;, but most importantly I still consider it &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/possibly-the-most-fun-ive-had-professionally&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;among the most rewarding things I&amp;#8217;ve done&lt;/a&gt;. From a purely stats perspective, I think my productivity can be summed up as a strong start, medium middle, and lacking end. I thought it would be fun to look at some concrete numbers, so here is what I came up with.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>3 Months of Game Development Statistics</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/3-months-of-game-development-statistics/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Jul 2014 18:18:38 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/3-months-of-game-development-statistics/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;m hoping make my game development process transparent as possible, so on a quarterly basis I plan to publish some figures related to productivity, marketing, code count, and anything else that may be relevant to other game developers out there. So without further ado, here are some stats related to my first three months of game development.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can a Mobile Game Have a Great Story?</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/can-a-mobile-game-have-a-great-story/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2014 13:50:30 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/can-a-mobile-game-have-a-great-story/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Forget the big ports like X-Com or Final Fantasy Tactics and you&amp;#8217;re left with mediocre stories in most mobile games. Hits like Angry Birds and Fruit Ninja excel in gameplay, not story. Even standout indie games like Hunters and Battleheart fall short. I expect almost every mobile game I buy to be light on gameplay and even lighter on story. I thought the same would be true for my game, but &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-Adventures-Princess-Mr-Whiffle/product-reviews/0983613125/ref=dp_top_cm_cr_acr_txt?ie=UTF8&amp;showViewpoints=1&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;The Adventures of Princess and Mr. Whiffle &lt;/a&gt;by Patrick Rothfuss changes everything.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>4 Tips from The App Store Playbook</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/4-tips-from-the-app-store-playbook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Apr 2014 16:06:43 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/4-tips-from-the-app-store-playbook/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I recently bought &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.amazon.com/The-App-Store-Playbook-Successful-ebook/dp/B009P1YPGK&#34;&gt;The App Store Playbook&lt;/a&gt;, written by Shane Lee, because &lt;a href=&#34;https://itunes.apple.com/us/app/hunters-2/id489463556?mt=8&#34;&gt;Hunters&lt;/a&gt; was highlighted and it&amp;#8217;s one of my favorite iPad games. Fortunately for me, the other 9 interviews were all solid, and I came away with some good indie game dev tips that I thought I&amp;#8217;d share.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Possibly the Most Fun I’ve Had Professionally</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/possibly-the-most-fun-ive-had-professionally/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2014 12:18:18 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/possibly-the-most-fun-ive-had-professionally/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was going to sit down this morning and write a post on why I&amp;#8217;m choosing Sprite Kit, but instead I feel the need to express how fun game development has been so far. It will be interesting to track my mood over time because I do see the tedious nature of the craft lurking around the corner, but for now I&amp;#8217;m loving life.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Chose the Corona SDK over Sprite Kit, Unity, or Cocos2d-x</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/why-i-chose-the-corona-sdk-over-sprite-kit-unity-or-cocos2d-x/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Apr 2014 15:17:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/why-i-chose-the-corona-sdk-over-sprite-kit-unity-or-cocos2d-x/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;#8217;ve spent the last couple of weeks testing out different 2d game development frameworks, and I&amp;#8217;ve decided that the &lt;a href=&#34;http://coronalabs.com/products/corona-sdk/&#34;&gt;Corona SDK&lt;/a&gt; is the tool for me. I was hoping there would be a standout framework that could make basic 2d games much better than the others, but I feel they each have pros and cons and they can all make games just fine. What it really comes down to is what makes me comfortable and excited about game development. I&amp;#8217;m not qualified to list out the &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.raywenderlich.com/67585/cocos2d-vs-sprite-kit-vs-unity-2d-tech-talk-video&#34;&gt;pros and cons of each environment&lt;/a&gt;, since I&amp;#8217;ve been developing games for all of two weeks, but I can tell you why Corona won my business.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let’s Do This!</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/lets-do-this/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 15:04:17 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/lets-do-this/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;April has been in my sights for some time now. After a move, some traveling, a bit of relaxation, building out an office space and designing this site, I&amp;#8217;m finally ready to start working on games. Actually, this dream is a lifetime in the making.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How Designing This Site Prepares Me For Game Development</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/how-designing-this-site-prepares-me-for-game-development/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 15:00:33 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/how-designing-this-site-prepares-me-for-game-development/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Whether it be video games, web development or mobile software, coding is coding. And launching something is hard. Every developer knows that. One of the main difficulties comes from design. Or, more specifically, polish. Anytime I can exercise my design muscles, I&amp;#8217;ll be better prepared the next time around.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Predictions About the Upcoming Year</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/this-is-how-i-see-the-year-playing-out/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2014 14:59:46 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirryan/this-is-how-i-see-the-year-playing-out/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One of the interesting parts of documenting a journey is seeing how wrong (or right) you can be in the beginning. Whether it be budget, timing, quality, success, enjoyment or one of the many other measurements &amp;#8212; something will not go as planned. I thought it would be fun to try to write out some concrete guesses about the future so that they can be revisited.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Expectations</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/expectations/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:56:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/expectations/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The official winner of this competition (and bragging rights) is going to be the brother whose game makes the most money, but all won&amp;#8217;t be lost if I come closer to my end goal of becoming a game developer. &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.brainyquote.com/quotes/quotes/b/brucelee385747.html&#34;&gt;Bruce Lee&lt;/a&gt; said that, &amp;#8220;a goal is not always meant to be reached, it often serves simply as something to aim at&amp;#8221;, and here are the targets that I&amp;#8217;ve set out to hit.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why I Blog</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/why-i-blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/why-i-blog/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Ryan and I decided to hold this competition, the first thing we did was create this blog. It was tempting test game development frameworks, prototype, or do anything actually related to game development, but we know first hand the benefits of blogging on both yourself and your product. Blogging does cut into precious development time, but I believe the benefits outweigh the costs for a number of reasons.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I’m a n00b</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/im-a-n00b/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:53:44 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/im-a-n00b/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;All journeys have beginnings and today is where my journey starts. While I might not be as useless as the n00b &lt;a href=&#34;http://www.wizards.com/Magic/tcg/newtomagic.aspx&#34;&gt;MTG&lt;/a&gt; card above, I do lack most of the skills required to build a video game. Advancing from beginner to competent game developer will be a difficult task, but I&amp;#8217;m hoping that&amp;#8217;s where this quest leads.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to the Site!</title>
      <link>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/welcome-to-the-site/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2014 16:40:22 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://battleofbrothers.com/sirchris/welcome-to-the-site/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Hi there, I&amp;#8217;m Chris and welcome to my game development blog. In case you came directly to this site and not through the &lt;a href=&#34;http://battleofbrothers.com&#34;&gt;splash page&lt;/a&gt;, let me give you a quick intro as to what&amp;#8217;s going on.
&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>